TAE-HYUNG KIM

Mobile: 236-777-7249 E-mail: taehyungkim@outlook.com Address: 9962 No.4 Rd, Richmond, British Columbia V7A 2Z3

taehyungalexkim.github.io

OBJECTIVE

Highly accomplished, multifaceted developer with over four years of experience for a private company and seven years at the Republic of Korea Army, seeking a IT Programmer position. Associate's degree in Internet Applications and Web Development in Canada and a bachelor's degree in Computer Science in Korea

Qualification summary

- Javascript, PHP, Node.js, MSSQL, C#
- Database Design, Maintenance and Tunning
- AWS, CodeDeploy, Travis CI, Github
- Azure Database Certification
- Major IT Project Management
- Team Building and Conflict Resolution

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fanshawe College, London, ON

Jan. 2020 – Apr. 2021

Lead Developer

- Lead various projects with inexperienced students as an experienced developer.
- Lead commercial web site production project: M-C dairy
- Responsible for organizing the overall development environment such as AWS, Github, CodeDeploy and Travis
- Final GPA: 4.15/4.2

ACS Corporation, Seoul, Korea

Aug. 2014 – Sept. 2018

Project Manager/Lead Developer

- Contributed significantly as a programmer/developer at ACS Corporation for over four years.
- Managed various duties as a project manager, including clients' needs assessment, technical evaluation, designing of software logic, assigning tasks to junior developer, troubleshooting, and final delivery of solutions to clients.
- Assigned to manage top clients, including Amore Pacific, Hyundai Kefico, Hyundai Powertech,
 Pulmuone, and others for major projects.
- Please refer to the below "Project Summary" for work description and achievements.

Republic of Korea Army, Korea

Mar. 2007 - Jul. 2014

Officer (Captain)

- Took charge of design and development of the system used in "battle" during the war. Oversaw the interface with other systems.
- Served as team leader of the supervision team when the software is developed or delivered throughout the army.
- Recognized as an excellent leader and won commendation (three times) from the Minister of National Defense and twice from the President.
- Took charge of development and operation of the logistics support system based on PHP and graphic DB.

PROJECT SUMMARY

Amore Pacific's WMS System Development Project

Period: Jan. 2018 – Sept. 2018

Technologies: • Designed MSSQL Database - inventory and order management, interface.

• For inventory management, the load on MSSQL is reduced by dividing the inventory table into 'input', 'output', and 'stock master' and using triggers to control the creation and deletion of inventory.

Project Tasks:

- Took charge of deploying automated warehouse solutions of KNAPP, a global company that specializes in automated storage, to Amore Pacific.
- Served as a project leader, improving the existing logistics process to fit the new system and headed the development of PDA programs.
- Handled interface design between ERP and WMS software.
- Instructed and provided technical advice to junior staff members and clients.

Kyung Dong Navien's Smart Factory Project

Period: Sept. 2017 – Dec. 2017

Technologies: • MSSQL

- o Implemented logic for predicting failure occurrence in MSSQL trigger.
- Reduced cost by adding a computed column to the [Quality measures table] and assigning an index.

Project Tasks:

- Developed additional system to existing MES for forecasting of a potential breakdown of mechanical facilities.
- Managed key functions as a project manager, including designing software logic
- Instructed and provided technical advice to junior staff members and clients.

Hyundai Kefico's MES Advancement Project in Vietnam

Period: Apr. 2017 – Sept. 2017

Technologies: • MSSQL

- o Designed database for electronic documents and reports.
- o Wrote stored procedures for electronic documents and reports.
- ASP.Net
 - o Computerized process documents used in factories using ComponentOne.
 - Realization of PDF documenting function of electronic documents and electronic signage display function.

Project Tasks:

- Development of a program to digitize various attached documents and reports.
- Effectively served as a project leader, heading the database design, interface design, and document authentication system.

Namyang Nexmo's MES System Development Project in Poland

Period: Sept. 2016 – Mar. 2017

Technologies: • MSSQL

- o Managed the server costs using SQL Sentry Plan Explorer.
- o Wrote stored procedures for PDA Programs.
- o Created middleware programs for MSSQL(Poland)-MSSQL(Korea) interface.
- C#
 - o Dedicated to creating Windows Mobile PDA program.

Page 3

o Established the interface procedure between QMS and MES.

Project Tasks:

- Development of MES system for a factory in Poland of Namyang Nexmo, a major subcontractor of Hyundai and Kia Motors.
- Managed various duties as the main program developer, including all phases of the logistics process from warehousing and shipment of parts to returns, processing, and final delivery and development of software.
- Took charge of the design and development of data interlink between Korea and Poland.
- PDA in Polish and English version.

BMI's New Vehicle Model Tracking Management System Project

Period: Aug. 2016

Technologies: • Database - Add quality information to database and adjust interface entries.

• Performed Visual Basic software reverse engineering.

Project Tasks: • Headed the task of linking BMI databases in conjunction with Hyundai/Kia Motors

systems when new vehicle models are added.

• Spearheaded the development of the Zebra barcode system.

Hyundai Powertech's Export-oriented Packing Yard Barcode System Project in Korea and China

Period: Jul. 2016

Technologies: • Database - Add quality information to database and adjust interface entries.

• ZPL - Adjusted barcode labels design.

Project Tasks: • Headed barcode system development, PDA development, and others.

Namyang Nexmo's MES System Development Project in Korea

Period: Aug. 2015 – Mar. 2016

Technologies: • MSSQL

o Managed the server costs using SQL Sentry Plan Explorer.

Wrote stored procedures for PDA Programs.

o Created middleware programs for MSSQL(MES)-Oracle(ERP) interface.

C#

Dedicated to creating Windows Mobile PDA program.

Project Tasks: • Head

• Headed all phases of logistics process design, PDA development, ERP-MES interface program development, and others.

Hyundai Powertech's All Plants CPMS Improvement Project

Period: Dec. 2014 – Apr. 2015

Technologies: • MSSQL Tunning

- o Database migration from Oracle to MSSQL using ISPIRER.
- o Changed the 'Line status' query to an indexed view.
- Reduced cost by adding a computed column to the [Quality check result table] and assigning an index.
- C#
 - o Designed program basic configuration (login, tab, etc.).
 - o Dedicated to creating software for inventory management.

Project Tasks: • Headed the conversion of existing web-based MES system to C based.

• Served as a main program developer designing and developing the program's entire frame and conversion of Oracle databases to MSSQL.

Pulmuone's Raw Noodle Plant POP Development Project

Period: Sept. 2014 – Nov. 2014

Technologies: • Wrote MSSQL stored procedure for POP System.

• Created feature pages using ASP.Net.

Project Tasks: • Development of a POP system for a raw noodle production line.

• Served as a main program developer developing touch-type terminal system.

• Design of production process from flour to noodle.

EDUCATION

Fanshawe College, London, Canada

Jan. 2020 – Apr. 2021

Associate's degree in Internet Applications and Web Development.

Final GPA: 4.15/4.2, Dean's Honor Roll for all semesters

Hongik University, Seoul, Korea

Mar. 2003 - Feb.2007

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science. Minored in Business Administration. Recipient of Army scholarship.

SKILLS & LANGUAGES

- ☑ Database design, Maintenance and Tunning; MSSQL and Oracle
- ☑ ASP.Net, C#, Node.js, PHP, JavaScript, CI tools, Window mobile and others.
- ☑ Native in Korean and fluent in English

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- ☑ Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals(993150418)
- ☑ Engineer Information Communication, Korea Communications Agency
- ☑ Information Communication Technician (Advanced level), Korea Information & Communication Contractors Association
- ☑ Information Communication Supervisor (Advanced level), Korea Information & Communication Contractors Association

AWARDS & HONORS

- ☑ Commendation from the President of Korea
- ☑ Commendation (Three times) from the Minister of National Defense